<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terraform on Dave's DevOps blog</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on Dave's DevOps blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:40:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davehart.co.uk/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform: Multi-cloud demo - Part 1 - Foundations</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-1-foundations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:40:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-1-foundations/</guid><description>I have been fortunate enough to be given an opportunity to help colleagues at my workplace on their journey to HashiCorp Terraform Associate Certification.
As part of the training track being put together (Mostly centred around the great Pluralsight training material from Ned Bellavance) it seemed a demonstration of some of the capabilities of Terraform would be beneficial for those on their learning journey. I decided to write this article as it will supplement the live demo I will be performing on one of the training sessions and may be of use to anyone else on their journey.</description></item><item><title>Terraform, AWS and WordPress – Part II</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-aws-and-wordpress-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:27:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-aws-and-wordpress-part-ii/</guid><description>This is a continuation of Terraform, AWS and WordPress - Part I. Let look deeper under the covers and focus on what the bootstrap part of the deployment is doing.
user_data Just as a refresher, the userdata defined on an AWS EC2 instance is used to run commands or scripts on the instance when deployed. As we are deploying an Amazon Linux EC2 instance the commands will reflect this Operating System.
Setting the scene So lets carve the user_data into something we can read and work with and pop some remarks in.</description></item><item><title>First! Terraform, AWS and WordPress - Part I</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-aws-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 02:59:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-aws-wordpress/</guid><description>Well here we go then, where to start? It seemed only fitting that the first post covers the fun I had setting up this WordPress server and site. I looked around at some of the options available, payed hosting etc and decided that &amp;ldquo;hey, lets learn something and share the experience at the same time&amp;rdquo;. Rather than manually setting up and configure the server (easy), I decided to try automate it as much as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>