<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>demo on Dave's DevOps blog</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/tags/demo/</link><description>Recent content in demo on Dave's DevOps blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:49:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davehart.co.uk/tags/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform: Multi-cloud demo – Part 4 – AWS Instances</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-4-aws-instances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:49:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-4-aws-instances/</guid><description>Now we have our security groups and instance profile, lets look at creating our ec2 instances. We will be defining our own module which fits our requirements and introducing userdata and templatefile functions.
First we will setup and configure our modules main.tf (modules/instances/main.tf)
Module : instances 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 terraform { required_version =&amp;#34;&amp;gt;=0.14.8&amp;#34; } resource &amp;#34;aws_instance&amp;#34; &amp;#34;instance&amp;#34; {# aws_instance resource type ami = var.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Multi-cloud demo – Part 3 – AWS Infrastructure</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-3-aws-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 11:23:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-3-aws-infrastructure/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s going well so far. We have our source control defined and updated and our Terraform remote state hosted on Azure Storage which we provisioned using Terraform. Let&amp;rsquo;s now move onto provisioning our AWS infrastructure.
Root module main.tf First off we need to add the aws provider;
1 2 3 4 provider &amp;#34;aws&amp;#34; { region = var.region profile = var.profile } You will notice that we have also used a couple of variables with this provider.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Multi-cloud demo – Part 2 – Terraform Remote State on Azure</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-2-terraform-remote-state-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 08:57:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-2-terraform-remote-state-on-azure/</guid><description>So we have setup our source control (GitHub) for team collaboration (Part 1) , next we should consider the Terraform state file.
By Default Terraform will create a local state file (terraform.tfstate), this does not work when collaborating as each person needs to have the latest version of the state data prior to performing any Terraform actions. In addition you need to ensure that nobody else is running Terraform at the same time. Having a remote state helps mitigate these issues.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Multi-cloud demo - Part 1 - Foundations</title><link>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-1-foundations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:40:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davehart.co.uk/post/terraform-multi-cloud-demo-part-1-foundations/</guid><description>I have been fortunate enough to be given an opportunity to help colleagues at my workplace on their journey to HashiCorp Terraform Associate Certification.
As part of the training track being put together (Mostly centred around the great Pluralsight training material from Ned Bellavance) it seemed a demonstration of some of the capabilities of Terraform would be beneficial for those on their learning journey. I decided to write this article as it will supplement the live demo I will be performing on one of the training sessions and may be of use to anyone else on their journey.</description></item></channel></rss>